<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-05-10T15:10:07+00:00</updated><id>https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Tom’s Time Capsule</title><subtitle>github blog with jekyll-paginate-v2 (supports paginations for multiple categories) will link it to the github blog site via Travis)</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Finished a blog project</title><link href="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/10/Finished-building-up-a-blog" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Finished a blog project" /><published>2021-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/10/Finished%20building%20up%20a%20blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/10/Finished-building-up-a-blog">&lt;!-- prettier-ignore --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;checkbox yellow&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Today&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Implemented additional minor features(comment section with Disqus(?)/email address clipboard copy) to the blog&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Added Responsiveness to the blog(small,medium,(deault),large sizes)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;checkbox blue&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Tommorrow&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Implement Fixed ^Top Icon on the right bottom of the blog&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Try solving 3 LeetCode problem(related to 2 topics: String Manipulation,
      Merge Sort)
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;!-- excerpt-start --&gt;
  Finally, I see the end of this project though there won't be end if i really
  purse the perfection. But, at least for now, except the fixed ^Top icon
  button, Basic functionalities of blog are implemented I think. More than
  anything, I found myself spending too much time mostly on visual design, which
  shouldn't be my priority though I enjoyed doing it. I've got tons of things to
  learn and I am still even not good with Javascript. So I think i will just
  wrap this project up this point.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  Since I started building this blog up last Monday. It took exactly about a
  week for me to build this blog. I really didn't expect it to take this much
  time since I already knew how to create static pages with html/css/js.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  It took a bit of time until I feel like digging a rabbit hole. Firstly, I
  learnt that Github Pages is run with Jekyll, so I picked it up. Soon, I also
  realized that I need to use bit of Liquid to use Jekyll efficiently.. So i
  picked up bit of Liquid and that wasnt the end of course. Jekyll Plugins, Git
  submodule, Travis CI.. I've learnt much more than I expected from the project.
  I still don't think I really picked up Everything completly. But, at least, I
  think I understand most of them on a conceptual level and I feel now bit
  confident with Jekyll and Liquid though I am not sure when I will use it again
  &lt;br /&gt;
  Since I started studying CS at Uni, I really didn't have enough time or mental
  energy. I managed to pass the courses fortunetely, but was mostly at the brink
  of mental breakdown due to my personal problems. Thanks to Corona virus, now I
  came back home and and finally picking up the broken pieces of myself with the
  help of my family. And this is the first project ever I've done myself from
  the start to the end. Hope that this would be the turning point to put my life
  back on the route. Never Give up !
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tom TakA</name></author><category term="Daily" /><summary type="html">Today Implemented additional minor features(comment section with Disqus(?)/email address clipboard copy) to the blog Added Responsiveness to the blog(small,medium,(deault),large sizes)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Let’s Finish</title><link href="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/09/Let's-Finish" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let’s Finish" /><published>2021-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/09/Let's%20Finish</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/09/Let's-Finish">&lt;!-- prettier-ignore --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;checkbox yellow&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Today&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Blog - navBar current feature implemented&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Blog - navBar total posts display feature implemented&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Blog - Post design finished and implmented Post template based on the design&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Blog - Implemented sub-pagination feature in Post Design&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fixed bugs with regards to the navBar route&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;checkbox blue&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Tommorrow&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fix minor bug with navBar completely&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Design and implement a header to the blog&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Add a comment feature on each post&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Try wrapping up the project by finishing above 3 features&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Try solving 2 LeetCode problems (Trie/Stack/Queue)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;!-- excerpt-start --&gt;
  It was too busy today.. and its alreayd almost 2am.. All i did was to
  implement features on my blog. I can see some progresses and feel that i
  almost finished this project. Lets wrap it up till wednesday..
  &lt;br /&gt;
  btw.. i really need to do some DS/Algo on LeetCode :..(
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tom TakA</name></author><category term="Daily" /><summary type="html">Today Blog - navBar current feature implemented Blog - navBar total posts display feature implemented Blog - Post design finished and implmented Post template based on the design Blog - Implemented sub-pagination feature in Post Design Fixed bugs with regards to the navBar route</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Reset</title><link href="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/08/Reset" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Reset" /><published>2021-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/08/Reset</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/08/Reset">&lt;!-- prettier-ignore --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;checkbox yellow&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Today&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Blog website finally working with Travis CI&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Documented Blog Project on Word - need to put it up here on the blog later&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;checkbox blue&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Tommorrow&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Finish Designing/Implementing Post/Footer Section of Blog&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Make the blog responsive to various viewport sizes(Web/Tab/Mobile)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Try solving 2 LeetCode problems (Trie/Stack/Queue)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;!-- excerpt-start --&gt;
  Today was very confusing day with ups and downs. At least till this morning, I
  was so happy that I finally get my blog work with Travis CI, which was the
  most hardest part for me. And The only thing left for me to do was just same
  designing and implementing phase for post/footer and bit of media queries to
  make the blog site responsive.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  Being hopeful, after lunch, I strated documenting what I've done so far in the
  project for the future reference and to record my learnings from this project.
  And it was also not that bad, I quite enjoyed writing it out.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  And after that, around dinner time, eveyrthing started getting hairy all of a
  sudden.. My vscode terminal starts not showing anything just being blank for
  no reason. And that completely sent me on a wild-goose chase since it turned
  out that there was nothing wrong with me, rahter it was due to some mysterious
  incompatibility existing between VS Code and my zsh theme (10k sth whatever).
  &lt;br /&gt;
  Till I finally figured that out, I literally uninstalled and installed
  everything suspcious.. literally everything.. I firstly reset my zsh thinking
  i might've modified some parts accidentally and VS Code after that. In the
  end, after finding out what is the cause, i had to revert every set up env
  back to what they were which was another pain in the neck 😥😥.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  Anyway... I'm just trying to think that it was an another good revision of how
  VS Code work and zsh.. (&lt;strike&gt;Nope&lt;/strike&gt;).
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tom Tak</name></author><category term="Daily" /><summary type="html">Today Blog website finally working with Travis CI Documented Blog Project on Word - need to put it up here on the blog later</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Dummy LeetCode!</title><link href="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/computer%20science/leetcode/2021/05/07/Trie" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Dummy LeetCode!" /><published>2021-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/computer%20science/leetcode/2021/05/07/Trie</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/computer%20science/leetcode/2021/05/07/Trie">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;today&quot;&gt;Today&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul style=&quot;margin-left: 2rem&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&quot;Home(Index)&quot; Page - Finished Implementing Pagination(Functionality &amp;amp; Design)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Figured Out Jekyll File Structure with regards to post folder location&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Navbar Links Implemented&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trie LeetCode problem (212 Revision with solution(plain + optimized version)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tommorrow&quot;&gt;Tommorrow&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul style=&quot;margin-left: 2rem&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Configure the common template for category main page/ post page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Finishing Designing and Implementing post.html&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Try solving 2 LeetCode problems (Trie/Stack/Queue)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;blah-blah-blah&quot;&gt;Blah, Blah, Blah&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;padding-left: 15px;&quot;&gt;
&lt;!-- excerpt-start --&gt;
Nowadays, i keep studying more than 8 hrs per day though i bludges for a while in the day.
I think its mainly due to the blog project since it just eats up large chunk of time easily. And I dont think i am fully concentrated while i'm doing the project compared to taking a course since all i do for project is mostly a series of &quot;Googling &amp;amp; Being Frustrated for a while&quot;. 
&lt;br /&gt;
Anyhow, hope i can finally finish template files for post. So, I would not need to manually template the post like now i'm doing. And i think i'm putting too much time on learning this jekyll &amp;amp; liquid stuffs rather than practicing html/css/js which i originally wanted to do.
&lt;br /&gt;
I better finish this project asap so that I can practice more on html/css/js before moving on to js. At the moment, I'm thinking of cloning some popular website for practices like i was doing with starbuck page.(Hmm i probs should restart the project again once i finish this)
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name>Tom Tak</name></author><category term="Computer Science" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Keep Going!</title><link href="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/05/Keep-goin" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keep Going!" /><published>2021-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/05/Keep%20goin</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/05/Keep-goin">&lt;!-- prettier-ignore --&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;checkbox yellow&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Today&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&quot;Home(Index)&quot; Page - Finished Implementing Pagination(Functionality &amp; Design)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Figured Out Jekyll File Structure with regards to post folder location&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Navbar Links Implemented&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Trie LeetCode problem (212 Revision with solution(plain + optimized version)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;checkbox blue&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Tommorrow&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Configure the common template for category main page/ post page&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Finishing Designing and Implementing post.html&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Try solving 2 LeetCode problems (Trie/Stack/Queue)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- excerpt-start --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Nowadays, i keep studying more than 8 hrs per day though i bludges for a while
  in the day. I think its mainly due to the blog project since it just eats up
  large chunk of time easily. And I dont think i am fully concentrated while i'm
  doing the project compared to taking a course since all i do for project is
  mostly a series of &quot;Googling &amp; Being Frustrated for a while&quot;.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  Anyhow, hope i can finally finish template files for post. So, I would not
  need to manually template the post like now i'm doing. And i think i'm putting
  too much time on learning this jekyll &amp; liquid stuffs rather than practicing
  html/css/js which i originally wanted to do.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  I better finish this project asap so that I can practice more on html/css/js
  before moving on to js. At the moment, I'm thinking of cloning some popular
  website for practices like i was doing with starbuck page.(Hmm i probs should
  restart the project again once i finish this)
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tom Tak</name></author><category term="Daily" /><summary type="html">Today &quot;Home(Index)&quot; Page - Finished Implementing Pagination(Functionality &amp; Design) Figured Out Jekyll File Structure with regards to post folder location Navbar Links Implemented Trie LeetCode problem (212 Revision with solution(plain + optimized version)</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Having Fun!</title><link href="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/04/Having-Fun" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Having Fun!" /><published>2021-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/04/Having%20Fun</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/04/Having-Fun">&lt;div class=&quot;checkbox yellow&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Today&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Complete a basic skeleton structure of a blog&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Implemented Header/Profile/Navbar(Design Structure Only)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;
      Tried 2 Trie LeetCode problems (211 solved, 212 TLE for the worst case)
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;checkbox blue&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Tommorrow&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Complete &quot;Latest Post&quot; section in &quot;Home&quot; Page&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Make Navbar fully functional - make a href links work&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Try solving 2 Trie problmes (212 and the other) in Leetcode&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- excerpt-start --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Finally I made up my mind on a blog design. Actually for me, designing my blog
  was much harder than just coding it up since I'm kinda perfectionist :.. (
  Anyway, i couldn't keep being stuck at the designing stage forever, so i
  managed to compromised myself with a basic and commmon design structure.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  Before then, my imagination kinda exploded and i was thinking of lots of crazy
  themes for my blog, which must be difficult to implement as well. Those were
  simply not feasible considering my current skillset. I would probably end up
  procrastinating after all since it would be too overwhelming to implement
  those shiny stuffs I imagined at first.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  And... tah da~~ The image below on this post is the blog design i drew myself
  before having started buidling this blog up today.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  I still need to change a bit of details on Latest Posts section and might add
  some more components to it but anyway.. At least it got me going and I'm glad
  i've moved on with this design. Not sure how my blog would look like to others
  yet, but at least to me it looks cool (my baby.. of course)
  &lt;br /&gt;
  I probably should work more on DS/Algo tomorrow though.. since i've been
  neglecting the subject since this blog project took too much time than i
  expected.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  Then .. this is all for today. Hope that i wouldn't need to manually format my
  daily post md file soon !! Gnight :))
  &lt;br /&gt;

  &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/blog-design.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;blog-design&quot; /&gt;
  (Hover over the Image to enlarge it 😁)
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tom Tak</name></author><category term="Daily" /><summary type="html">Today Complete a basic skeleton structure of a blog Implemented Header/Profile/Navbar(Design Structure Only) Tried 2 Trie LeetCode problems (211 solved, 212 TLE for the worst case)</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/assets/images/blog-design.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/assets/images/blog-design.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Burn Out</title><link href="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/03/Burnt-out" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Burn Out" /><published>2021-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/03/Burnt%20out</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/03/Burnt-out">&lt;div class=&quot;checkbox yellow&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Today&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Finished Taking Jekyll Tutorial&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Tried Medium level Trie Problem on LeetCode[Failed]&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;checkbox blue&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Tommorrow&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;[Morning] Finalize a blog design - Do not too be ambitious&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;[Afternoon] Start Implementing a header of a blog based on a design&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Try solving 2 problems(Trie/Stack/Queue) in Leetcode&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
  Today I was totally burnt out especially in the evening so i couldn't study
  enough for ds &amp; algo on leetcode.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  I feel like i should be more consistent. Take time and do things one by one. I
  will get there some day if i don't give up in the middle being burnt out.
&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Tom Tak</name></author><category term="Daily" /><summary type="html">Today Finished Taking Jekyll Tutorial Tried Medium level Trie Problem on LeetCode[Failed]</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/images/img1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/images/img1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Let’s Build!</title><link href="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/02/Let's-Build!" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Let’s Build!" /><published>2021-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2021-05-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/02/Let's%20Build!</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/daily/2021/2021/05/02/Let's-Build!">&lt;div class=&quot;checkbox yellow&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Today&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Configured Ruby &amp; Jekyll dev environment&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ready to start building up a blog with html/css(Sass)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;checkbox blue&quot;&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;title&quot;&gt;Tommorrow&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;ul class=&quot;list&quot;&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish the skeleton of my blog (Header/Body/Footer)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Focus on the structure rather than styling (Do this later)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try solving 2 problems(Trie/Stack/Queue) in Leetcode&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;!-- excerpt-start --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  Today, I finally started building my own blog, which has been always on my
  to-do-list, but never dare to start at least till yesterday. So, I wasn't
  planning to do this today at all though i thought i will at some point in the
  future.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  Initially, I simply thought that my front-end dev skills aren't good enough
  yet to build a blog wesbite since I'm actually still at a very early stage of
  front-end development. I just had finished the basics of HTML and CSS(Sass)
  course 2 days ago.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  Still, I kept thinking that I really need to blog my daily life or learning
  for many reasons. First one I could think of was that it might help me to get
  a job in the future since the recruiters might want to know how I've been
  studying so far and they would be able to check those easily from my blog.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  But, more than anything, it was to calm me down from being depressed and
  feeling anxious. I think I studied not that bad last month, but I kept feeling
  worried if I've been doing alright. So, I had to keep checking where I'm up to
  and how much i've done so far. And after a few days in that same mood, I
  finally realised that I need something visual to show the workloads I've done
  and the thing could be my blog since i will record my daily learning there and
  be able to check them easily if i want to.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  Anyway, so i tried buidling damn blog today. My original thought was to finish
  building it today within a few hours and how naive I was !! 😂😂 I already got
  stuck with installing ruby on my WSL, which was very painful. I bumped into
  lot of diffrent error messages which i barely could understand at all. I
  literally spent all my morning time wiht installing damn ruby on my WSL.
  &lt;br /&gt;
  Even after that, it again took me another few hours to figure out how jekyll
  exactly works with its own structure and liquid, which i've never seen before.
  Anyway, I finally figured it out now and its almost 12am 😥😥. And my blog
  website still looks very humble.. compared to my ambitious one in my
  imagination. Whatever :(( I still have a week right? (I changed my plan, so i
  will try building it up for a week)
  &lt;br /&gt;
  Ok, I better wrap it up here since I have tommorow to start!
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![img-1](/images/img1.jpg) --&gt;
&lt;!-- &lt;img src=&quot;/images/img1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;img-1&quot; /&gt; --&gt;</content><author><name>Tom Tak</name></author><category term="Daily" /><summary type="html">Today Configured Ruby &amp; Jekyll dev environment Ready to start building up a blog with html/css(Sass)</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/images/img1.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://xkrdudrlf.github.io/images/img1.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>